[music]
[音乐]
Hello and welcome to part 5 of
您好，欢迎阅读第5部分
lesson 3. In this section we're going to talk about parallel streams
第3课，在本节中，我们将讨论并行流
and one of the things that we really want to get across here is
我们真正想了解的一件事是
when to use them, but also when not to use them.
什么时候使用它们，什么时候不使用它们。
If we
要是我们
look back at how we can create stream sources
回头看看我们如何创建流源
you'll remember from lesson 2 that we saw that for a collection
您会从第2课中记得我们在collections中看到的
you could either create stream sequentially by calling the stream
您可以通过调用流来顺序创建流
method
方法
or you could create parallel stream. Now this is the
或者您可以创建并行流。现在这是
only way that you can create a parallel stream directly
您可以直接创建并行流的唯一方法
as a source. Other ways of creating stream sources
作为来源。创建流源的其他方式
don't allow you to create parallel one directly. What this provides us with
不允许您直接创建并行之一。这为我们提供了什么
is
是
a situation, where if we want to have a parallel stream
一种情况，如果我们想要并行流
but we've created it from say an array rather than a collection,
但是我们是用数组而不是集合创建的，
how do we make parallel? In that case there is a method
我们如何使并行？在这种情况下，有一种方法
in the stream interface called parallel and that allows to convert
在称为parallel的流接口中，该接口允许转换
sequential stream into a parallel stream. There's also the opposite of that,
顺序流转换为并行流。与此相反，
where we have a parallel stream already we can convert it into a sequential
在已经有并行流的地方，我们可以将其转换为顺序流
stream.
流。
So we can use the sequential method to do that. If we have multiple calls within
因此，我们可以使用顺序方法来做到这一点。如果我们有多个电话
our code
我们的代码
where we're changing between parallel streams and sequential streams
在并行流和顺序流之间进行切换的地方
quite possible then whichever is the last
很有可能那么最后一个
call will be the one that actually wins, because
通话将是真正获胜的电话，因为
all with the stream is going to be processed
所有与流将被处理
either sequentially or in parallel. It isn't a case of we'll process the first few
顺序或并行。不是这种情况，我们将处理前几个
parts in parallel
并联零件
then we'll switch to sequential, then we'll switch back to parallel. It doesn't work like
然后我们将切换到顺序，然后再切换回并行。它不像
that.
那。
Everything is either sequential or everything is either parallel.
一切都是顺序的，或者一切都是并行的。
Whichever is the last change that you make
您最后所做的更改是哪一个
to the way the stream is processed that will be the one
流的处理方式将是
which all the stream will be processed as.
所有流将被处理为。
If you concantenate two streams
如果合并两个流
then, if you have one of them
然后，如果您有其中之一
sequential and one of them parallel, the result
顺序和其中之一并行，结果
will be a parallel stream. In terms
将是并行流。在条款上
of how parallel streams are implemented
如何实现并行流
they use the fork-join framework underneath.
他们在下面使用fork-join框架。
The library code will use the fork-join framework to
库代码将使用fork-join框架来
break up whatever task is being handled
分解正在处理的任务
into a number subtasks, allocate those
分成多个子任务，分配那些
to a pool of threads through queues, have those processed
到队列中的线程池，处理那些
in parallel, take all the results when they're ready
并行，准备好所有结果
and create an output. The way this works
并创建一个输出。工作方式
is that the number of threads,
是线程数，
which allocated in the pool, is based purely
分配在池中的纯基于
on how many processors the operating system reports.
操作系统报告的处理器数量。
If you have a dual core machine, which
如果您有双核计算机，
also does hyper threading, you'll actually get
也会做超线程，实际上
four processors reported, so the pool size will be
报告了四个处理器，因此池大小为
four threads. That may not be what you want.
四个线程。那可能不是您想要的。
If you are running on a big machine, where you have
如果您在大型计算机上运行，
many processors and many cores you may not want all of them
许多处理器和许多核心，您可能不希望全部使用
dedicated to one task in one application.
致力于一个应用程序中的一项任务。
It's not particularly easy to
这不是特别容易
to change this; so it would be nice if there was a simple way of doing this, but there is a
改变这个；因此，如果有一个简单的方法可以做到这一点，但是有一个
kind of work around
周围的工作
that you can use. You can set a system
您可以使用的。您可以设置系统
property using System.setProperty and as you can see here you can change
属性使用System.setProperty，如您所见，您可以在此处进行更改
the common parallelism number
通用并行数
that's associated with the fork-join pool. You can change that
与fork-join池相关联。你可以改变
from any number from 0 to 32767
从0到32767之间的任何数字
and you can set that to be whatever you want. if you have 16 cores,
您可以将其设置为所需的任何值。如果您有16个核心，
16 processors in the machine then you could maybe set
机器中有16个处理器，则可以设置
that to 4 or set it to 8, depending on
设置为4或将其设置为8，具体取决于
what you want to do. One of the most important things about parallel streams
你想做什么。并行流最重要的事情之一
is not to be misled by thinking
不要被思想误导
that parallel streams will always give you better performance.
并行流将始终为您提供更好的性能。
If you have a machine with multiple cores and multiple processors
如果您的机器具有多个核心和多个处理器
you might be tempted to go, well I can always do things in parallel
你可能很想去，好吧，我总是可以并行做事
and that would give me better results. That's not necessarily the case.
那会给我更好的结果。不一定是这样。
Because you need to remember that
因为你要记住
regardless of what happens parallel stream
不管并行流发生什么
will always involved doing more work because,
总是会做更多的工作，因为，
in the case using the fork-join framework, all of that
在使用fork-join框架的情况下，所有这些
has overhead. You have to set up the framework, set up all
有开销。您必须设置框架，设置所有
the threads in the pool, to allocate jobs to the
池中的线程，以将作业分配给
different queues and so on. The thing about using
不同的队列等等。关于使用的事情
parallel stream is that, although it always involves more work
并行流是，尽管它总是涉及更多工作
sometimes it will finish more quickly then if you do it sequentially.
有时，如果您依次执行，它会更快地完成。
Considerations
注意事项
for using parallel streams and there are a couple of things you need to do here.
使用并行流，这里需要做几件事。
We've talked about findFirst and findAny
我们已经讨论过findFirst和findAny
as terminal methods
作为终端方法
in the stream. I mentioned when we talk about that findAny
在流中。当我们谈论那个发现时我提到过
is non-deterministic; what that means is that you have several threads,
是不确定的；这意味着您有多个线程，
all looking for a result. Any of those threads
所有人都在寻找结果。这些线程中的任何一个
can generate a result as soon as it finds it. That means that
可以立即找到结果。那意味着
if you use the same input data and you run it several times with the same data
如果您使用相同的输入数据，并且使用相同的数据运行几次
you won't necessarily get the same result if you use findFirst
如果使用findFirst，不一定会得到相同的结果
even with the parallel stream you will get a deterministic result.
即使使用并行流，您也将获得确定的结果。
The result for the same input stream set of data will always be the same.
同一输入流数据集的结果将始终相同。
That's something to remember, something to consider when you design your stream
这是要记住的事，在设计流时要考虑的事
code.
码。
Same thing with forEach
与forEach同样
and there is an equivalent method called forEachOrdered.
并且有一个等效的方法称为forEachOrdered。
If you use forEach and parallel stream
如果使用forEach和并行流
and you have ordered data you will get
您已经订购了数据，您将获得
non deterministic results. If you take a list
非确定性结果。如果您列出清单
and you call forEach on the stream from that list
然后您从该列表中调用forEach
you won't necessarily if you're using parallel threads
如果使用并行线程，则不一定
get the same order if you print out the results.
如果打印出结果，则得到相同的顺序。
If you want that then you can use forEachOrdered,
如果您愿意，可以使用forEachOrdered，
which again is deterministic. If you take a list
这又是确定性的。如果您列出清单
and create parallel stream from that pass it to forEachOrdered
并从中创建并行流并将其传递给forEachOrdered
and print out the elements you always get beyond in the same order
并以相同的顺序打印出您总是可以超越的元素
for the same input set. When to use parallel streams?
对于相同的输入集。什么时候使用并行流？
Unfortunately, there isn't really a simple answer to this.
不幸的是，对此没有真正简单的答案。
What you need to do is consider several things
您需要做的是考虑几件事
you need to consider what type of
您需要考虑什么类型的
data structure you're working with. If you have
您正在使用的数据结构。如果你有
something like an ArrayList as the source of your stream that's good
像ArrayList这样的流源很好
for parallel streams because it's easy to extract the data
用于并行流，因为很容易提取数据
in parallel way. HashSets and TreeSets
以并行方式。哈希集和树集
are not as good as ArrayList but they're OK. Things like a LinkedList
虽然不如ArrayList好，但是还可以。像LinkedList这样的东西
are bad because of the fact we have to follow all the links down
不好是因为我们必须遵循所有链接
the data structure in order to get to a particular value.
数据结构以便获得特定值。
That doesn't work well in parallel environment.
这在并行环境中无法很好地工作。
What you do in terms of the operations on your stream
就流中的操作而言，您要做的是
also will have an impact on how well
也将影响到
a parallel stream works versus sequential streams. If you're using things like
并行流与顺序流比较有效。如果您正在使用类似
filtering,
过滤
if you're using things like mapping these are
如果您正在使用诸如映射之类的东西，这些是
excellent for parallel streams. You can take those operations and
非常适合并行流。您可以执行这些操作，
you can decompose them completely into separate operations. The
您可以将它们完全分解为单独的操作。的
reason for that is that when you're doing a mapping,
原因是当您进行映射时，
you're mapping each individual element; there's no reliance between one element
您正在映射每个单独的元素；一个要素之间没有依赖
in the stream
在流中
and another. If you use things like sorted
还有一个。如果您使用排序
and distinct those don't decompose so well,
和那些分解得不太好的人
because there is a reliance on other elements in the
因为对其他元素的依赖
input set in order to construct the result. If you're looking for distinct
输入集以构造结果。如果您正在寻找与众不同的产品
data
数据
then you've got to make sure you've compared every element against all
那么您必须确保已将每个元素与所有元素进行了比较
other elements that you had so far in order to determine if its a
到目前为止，您需要确定其他元素
duplicate or not.
是否重复。
We also need to think about
我们还需要考虑
how much data we're using and how much time it takes to process each element.
我们正在使用多少数据以及处理每个元素需要多少时间。
If you think of the size of your data set as being
如果您认为数据集的大小
n and the cost of processing one element for your stream
n和为流处理一个元素的成本
pipelines is q, then the total cost
管道是q，那么总成本
of the work involved in processing this is going to be n*q.
处理该过程的工作量将为n * q。
The bigger the n*q
n * q越大
is the better parallel streams going to perform. For giving example
是要执行的更好的并行流。举个例子
if you got a list with 10 elements in
如果您有一个包含10个元素的列表
it and its just doing a mapping, a simple mapping
它和它只是做一个映射，一个简单的映射
then converting it to a parallel stream isn't going to
然后将其转换为并行流不会
improve efficiency. If you got a million elements
提高效率。如果你有一百万个元素
in your input set and you've got something which is fairly heavy weight in
在您的输入集中，您得到了一些相当重的东西
terms of what you're doing
你在做什么
then you'll get a lot better performance from parallel stream
那么您将从并行流中获得更好的性能
and it's easier
而且更容易
to determine n, because you can find out size of your data set
确定n，因为您可以找出数据集的大小
easily, but q can be quite difficult.
很容易，但是q可能很难。
You tend to end up estimating it. What you really need to do
您倾向于最终估计它。你真正需要做的
to ensure that you make the correct decision about where to use a parallel stream
以确保您正确决定在哪里使用并行流
or not is to
或不是
profile. Try it with a sequential stream, try it with parallel stream
轮廓。与顺序流一起尝试，与并行流一起尝试
and use whichever one is more efficient. To summarise section 5
并使用效率更高的一种。总结第5节
streams, as we have seen can be processed sequentially or they can be
如我们所见，流可以按顺序处理，也可以
processed in parallel.
并行处理。
When we say that we can switch between sequential
当我们说可以在顺序之间切换时
or parallel in the middle of a stream, but the stream will be processed
或在流中间平行，但将对流进行处理
either completely sequentially or completely in parallel.
完全顺序或完全并行。
Most cases when we use a stream
大多数情况下，我们使用流
how you define it won't effect the result; whether you do it sequentially or in parallel won't effect the
您如何定义它不会影响结果；依次执行还是并行执行都不会影响
result.
结果。
For findFirst, findAny, forEach and
对于findFirst，findAny，forEach和
forEachOrdered they will affect the order of the results.
forEachOrdered它们将影响结果的顺序。
And the big thing here it don't assume a
而这里的大事情并不假设
parallel stream will always return a faster result.
并行流将始终返回更快的结果。
As we've seen a number of factors that affect that
如我们所见，许多因素会影响到
and be careful in terms your choice
并谨慎选择
to make sure that you're using whichever is the most efficient.
以确保您使用的是最有效的。
And that is the end of this part of the lesson.
到此为止，这部分课程结束了。